Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/paulaauksutat (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Unternehmenskommunikation Employee Engagement Diversity & Inclusion

Certifications

Microsoft Teams Essential Training Accessibility in Action Microsoft Global Hackathon 2021 Creating a Positive Customer Experience

Confronting Bias: Thriving Across
Our Differences

Paula Auksutat

Communications Managerin @ Microsoft Deutschland GmbH | PR Report #30u30 2020

Munich

Summary

Creative and highly motivated communication young professional with growth mindset.

My key focus is to gain insights into emerging technologies and trends, strategic communication, and D&I.

As Communications Manager Employee Engagement at Microsoft Germany I am involved in projects in the areas of change communication, employee-generated content, social media, diversity & inclusion and social collaboration.

I also advocate inclusive and gender-sensitive language.

Co-Host @ comprimiert Podcast

Author and speaker at Hessischer Rundfunk for the format "Kirche in YOU FM".

I genuinely enjoy exploring new topics and am constantly looking forward to new challenges. An efficient organization and strategic approach characterize my work and me.

With my degree in "Communication Management" at the University of Leipzig, I was able to develop professionally a focus in the areas of strategic communication, communication controlling and digital media. Through my work experience, I was able to gain diverse experience in the comprehensive planning and successful implementation of specific PR activities alongside my academic studies.

Experience

Microsoft
1 year 10 months

Communications Managerin Employee Engagement October 2021 - Present (6 months)

München, Bayern, Deutschland

Trainee Employee Engagement

June 2020 - October 2021 (1 year 5 months)

München und Umgebung, Deutschland

Projects in the areas of change communication, employee-generated content, and social collaboration.

Hessischer Rundfunk

Writer and Speaker

September 2017 - Present (4 years 7 months)

Frankfurt am Main und Umgebung, Deutschland

Developed and realized a new radio report format for YOU FM "songcheck".

Editorial work and speaker.

Microsoft

1 year 1 month

Communications Working Student

September 2019 - March 2020 (7 months)

Berlin und Umgebung, Deutschland

Working Student PR & Communications

Communications Intern

March 2019 - August 2019 (6 months)

München und Umgebung, Deutschland

Internal and external communication focusing on Data & Al and educational topics.

Leipziger Public Relations Studenten e.V. (LPRS)

Vice Chairwoman

May 2018 - May 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Leipzig und Umgebung, Deutschland

Member of the executive board, head of events

Beauty Hills

2 years 2 months

PR-Assistent

April 2017 - March 2019 (2 years)

Hattersheim

Communication strategy, public relations and media relations, content management and SEO

Public Relations Intern February 2017 - April 2017 (3 months)

Frankfurt am Main und Umgebung, Deutschland

Start-up Communication: Developed and implemented a social media strategy

radioaktiv - Campusradio Rhein-Neckar e.V. Editor, Presenter and Head of the training department September 2013 - October 2017 (4 years 2 months) Mannheim und Umgebung, Deutschland

Head of the training department, recruiting, organizing workshops, editorial work, producing and hosting radio shows.

Universität Leipzig Research Assistant January 2017 - April 2017 (4 months) Leipzig und Umgebung, Deutschland

Working for Prof. Dr. (em.) Günter Bentele

Commerzbank AG Corporate Communications Intern July 2016 - January 2017 (7 months) Frankfurt am Main und Umgebung, Deutschland

Internal communication: focusing on change and diversity, human resources communication, content management

Tanzschule Müller Merkt
Assistant
February 2010 - June 2016 (6 years 5 months)
Darmstadt und Umgebung, Deutschland

Dance Instructor for ballroom dancing

Universität Mannheim Research Assistant March 2014 - May 2015 (1 year 3 months) Mannheim und Umgebung, Deutschland

Working for Prof. Dr. Vorderer

Research project "Mediatization Mobile", quantitativ and qualitative studies

DekaBank Deutsche Girozentrale Intern April 2011 - April 2011 (1 month) Frankfurt am Main und Umgebung, Deutschland

Education

Universität Leipzig

Master of Arts - MA, Communication Management · (2017 - 2020)

Universität Mannheim

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Kommunikation und Mediastudien · (2013 - 2017)

Pace University-New York

Semester abroad, Communication and media studies · (2015 - 2015)

Hong Kong Baptist University

Intercultural communication